<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Indian on Well lets take a look at it, Mr Gumby!</title>
    <link>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/food/indian/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Indian on Well lets take a look at it, Mr Gumby!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 00:41:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/food/indian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dal Box</title>
      <link>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/dal-box/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 22:40:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/dal-box/</guid>
      <description>This is inspired by the Helm Ston Cafe in Brighton which is bloody brilliant and you should all go buy his food.
Ingredients  2 tbsp rape seed oil 1 large white onion or 5 shallots - chopped fine 1.5 inch of ginger - chopped fine 2 cloves of garlic - chopped fine 1-2 red chilli&amp;rsquo;s 1 tsp black mustard seeds (optional) 1 tsp ground cumin 1 tsp ground coriander 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goan Fish Curry</title>
      <link>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/goan-fish-curry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 22:27:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/goan-fish-curry/</guid>
      <description>Recipe taken from Sanjeev Kapoor - Goan fish curry
Ingredients  Pomfret cut into darnes2 medium Oil 1 tablespoon Green chillies slit2 Onion finely chopped1 large Salt to taste Tamarind soaked and pulp removed1 lemon size Malt vinegar 2 teaspoons Steamed Basmati rice for serving Fresh coriander leaf for garnishing  For paste
 Dried red chillies 6 Cumin seeds 2 teaspoons Garlic 15 cloves Ginger roughly chopped 2 inch piece Coriander seeds 2 tablespoons Coconut scraped 1/2 cup  Method   To prepare paste, coarsely grind together dried red chillies, cumin seeds, garlic cloves, ginger, coriander seeds and coconut along with ¼ cup water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mushroom Butter Masala</title>
      <link>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/mushroom-butter-masala/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 19:21:36 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/mushroom-butter-masala/</guid>
      <description>Recipe based on recipe from: Sharm Passions - Mushroom butter masala
Ingredients  450g sliced mushrooms 50g butter 2 tsp cumin seeds 2 heaped tsp ginger garlic paste (6 cloves of garlic 3 inches cubed of ginger) 2 medium sized white onion chopped finely 4 tsp kashmiri chilli powder (if you dont have use 3 parts chilli powder 1 part paprika) 2 tsp garam masala powder 150ml fresh single cream salt to taste 8 medium sized tomatoes chopped roughly (640g) 20 cashews a pinch kasoori methi (or 1 tsp of maple syrup) coriander leaves chopped just to garnish  Method  Blend tomato and cashews into a paste and set aside Melt butter on a low/medium head and add the cumin seeds until they start popping Add Onion and cover pan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Palak Paneer</title>
      <link>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/palak-paneer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 20:17:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/palak-paneer/</guid>
      <description>This recipe comes from SKH Handicrafts from Sam&amp;rsquo;s trip to India in November 2019.
Ingredients  2 red onions finely chopped 2 large tomatoes roughly chopped 1 green chilli finely chopped 500g spinach 1 tbsp of garlic and ginger paste 1/2 tsp salt 1/2 tsp tumeric 1 tsp red chilli powder 1 tsp garam masala 350g paneer chopped into 2cm^3 cubes  Method  Wash the spinach and put to the side Fry onion, chilli and tomato in oil Add garlic and ginger paste Add 1/2 tsp of salt and tumeric Once cooked through, blend into a fine paste, add water if needed Wilt spinach in boiling water for 2 minute and blend into a paste Mix the two pastes together and heat in a pan on medium heat Add the chilli powder and garam masala Add salt to taste Add paneer and simmer for 5 minutes  Pictures </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paneer Butter Masala (Paneer Makhani)</title>
      <link>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/paneer-butter-masala-paneer-makhani/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 20:48:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/paneer-butter-masala-paneer-makhani/</guid>
      <description>This is one of my favourites so far! Doesn&amp;rsquo;t take too long to make and tastes brilliant!
Recipe taken from Cook with Manali! - Paneer Butter Masala
Ingredients  2 teaspoons oil, 10 ml, divided, I used avocado oil, use any flavorless oil 1 bay leaf 1/2 inch cinnamon stick 3-4 cloves 6-7 large garlic cloves, 25 grams, roughly chopped 1.5 inch ginger, 15 grams, roughly chopped 1 large white onion, 180 grams, roughly chopped 3-4 large tomatoes, 460 grams, roughly chopped 10-15 whole cashews, raw 1 cup water, 8 oz 2 tablespoons unsalted butter 1/2 teaspoon red chili powder 1/2 teaspoon kashmiri red chili powder 1/2 teaspoon garam masala, + 1/4 teaspoon, if needed 1/4 teaspoon cardamom powder 1 teaspoon sugar 3/4 teaspoon salt, or to taste 1/2 tablespoon tomato paste, optional 3-4 tablespoons cream, 45-60 ml 250 grams paneer, cut into cubes 2 teaspoons crushed kasuri methi, dried fenugreek leaves chopped cilantro, to garnish  Method   Heat 1 teaspoon of oil in a pan on medium heat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dal</title>
      <link>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/dal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2019 20:54:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/dal/</guid>
      <description>Recipe from my friend Abass.
Ingredients  165g split yellow dal 4 / 6 small Tomatoes - halved 2 cloves Garlic - finely chopped 1 inch Ginger - finely chopped 1 tspn Garam Masala 1 tspn Kashmiri Chilli 1 tspn Curry Powder 1 tspn Salted butter 450ml Water  Method   Melt butter on a low/medium heat and add garlic and ginger for two minutes
  Add spices and mix for 30 seconds</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kadai Paneer</title>
      <link>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/kadai-paneer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2019 18:24:36 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/kadai-paneer/</guid>
      <description>Recipe taken from Cook with Manali - Kadai Paneer
Ingredients Kadai Masala
 2 tablespoons coriander seeds 2 dried red chilies 4 green cardamom 1 teaspoon fennel seeds 3 cloves  Kadai Paneer
 1 tablespoon butter, unsalted 1 tablespoon oil, 15 ml, I used avocado oil 1 medium red onion, 150 grams, finely chopped 1 green chili, sliced 2 teaspoons ginger garlic paste 3-4 medium tomatoes, 450 grams, finely chopped 1 tablespoon tomato paste, optional 1/4 teaspoon garam masala 3/4 teaspoon kashmiri red chili powder 1 inch ginger, julienned, divided 1/2 cup water, 4 oz/120 ml 2 tablespoons heavy cream, 30 ml 3/4 teaspoon salt, or to taste 1 teaspoon sugar 1 large green bell pepper (capsicum), cut into 1-inch pieces 225 grams paneer, cubed, if using store-bought paneer soak it in warm water for 20-25 minutes before using 1 teaspoon kasuri methi, dried fenugreek leaves cilantro, to garnish  Method Make the Kadai Masala</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gobi Manchurian</title>
      <link>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/gobi-manchurian/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 10:58:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/gobi-manchurian/</guid>
      <description>Recipe taken from Cooking with Manali - Gobi Manchurian
Ingredients For the Sauce
 1 tablespoon avocado oil, or any oil of choice 1 tablespoon toasted sesame oil 1 tablespoon grated garlic 1 tablespoon grated ginger 1-2 green chilies, chopped 2 stalks celery, chopped 1 small red onion, chopped 1 medium green pepper, chopped 2-3 stalks scallions , chopped 2 tablespoons soy sauce, I used 1 tablespoon regular and 1 tablespoon dark soy sauce 2 tablespoons tomato ketchup 1 tablespoon rice vinegar 1 teaspoon sriracha or any hot sauce, adjust to taste 3/4 teaspoon sugar 1/8 teaspoon white pepper powder salt, to taste, if needed  For the Cauliflower Florets</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Onion Bhaji</title>
      <link>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/onion-bhaji/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2019 13:10:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/onion-bhaji/</guid>
      <description>Recipe taken from Good to Know - Onion Bhaji
Ingredients  6 level tbsp plain flour 1 level tsp turmeric 1 level tsp ground cumin 1 level tsp garam masala Salt and freshly ground black pepper 2 med onions, peeled and sliced Raita (minty yogurt), to serve, optional Deep-frying pan, with oil  Method   Heat the oil in the deep-frying pan to 190°C/375°F/Gas Mark 5.
  Mix the flour, spices and salt together in a bowl and add 3-4 tbsp water, to make a stiff batter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dal Makhani</title>
      <link>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/dal-makhani/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2019 12:44:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/dal-makhani/</guid>
      <description>Recipe taken from Cook With Manali - Dal Makhani
Ingredients To Pressure Cook
 3/4 cup urad dal sabut (whole black lentil), 165 grams 1/4 cup rajma (red kidney beans), 60 grams 1 teaspoon salt 3.5 cups water , 28 oz  Masala for the Dal.
 1 tablespoon ghee 3 tablespoons butter, divided, use amul butter (salted) if possible 1 medium white onion, 115 grams, finely grated using a food processor 2 teaspoons ginger garlic paste, use fresh paste if possible 1/2 cup tomato puree, use store bought tomato puree 1/2 teaspoon kashmiri red chili powder 1/4 teaspoon garam masala 1/2 teaspoon salt, or to taste 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fish Curry but with Aubergine!</title>
      <link>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/fish-curry-aubergine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 00:05:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/fish-curry-aubergine/</guid>
      <description>Recipe taken from: Telegraph - Rick Stein - Fish Curry
Ingredients  2 tbsp vegetable oil 1 tbsp yellow mustard seeds 1 large onion, finely chopped 3 garlic cloves, crushed 30 fresh curry leaves (from ethnic shops) 2 tsp Kashmiri chilli powder 1/2tsp hot chilli powder (see above) 2 tsp ground coriander 2 tsp turmeric 14oz/400g can chopped tomatoes 3 1/2floz/100ml tamarind water (see below) 2 green chillies, each sliced lengthways into 6 pieces, with seeds (leave these out if you are chilli-sensitive) 1 teaspoon salt lb 9oz/700g snapper fillets, or other white fish, cut into 5cm chunks or 2 aubergines to make it veggie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Andhra Spiced Egg Curry</title>
      <link>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/andhra-spiced-egg-curry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 19:21:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/andhra-spiced-egg-curry/</guid>
      <description>Recipe taken from: Mauni Kagowardhan - Andhra Spiced Egg Curry
Ingredients  3 eggs boiled, peeled and halved 2 vegetable oil 1 tsp mustard seeds 1 medium onion finely chopped (or 5-7 small shallots thinly sliced) 1 small cinnamon stick halved 2 green chillies slit lengthwise 2 tomatoes roughly chopped 1” piece ginger thinly sliced ½ tsp turmeric powder 1 tsp kashmiri chilli powder (or mild chilli powder) 1 tsp coriander powder 1 tsp tamarind concentrate 100mls water 50mls coconut milk 8-10 curry leaves Salt to taste  Method   Heat the oil in a heavy bottom sauce pan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sri Lankan Coconut Lentil Curry (Parippu Curry)</title>
      <link>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/sri-lanken-curry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 19:48:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/sri-lanken-curry/</guid>
      <description>Recipe taken from: The Bellephant - Sri Lankan Coconut Lentil Curry
Ingredients  450g red split lentils 1 litre water 1 tbsp ground cumin 2 tsp turmeric 250ml coconut cream 2tbsp coconut oil 2 onions, sliced 4-6 cloves garlic, minced 3 green chillies, finely chopped 2 tsp mustard seeds 2 tsp cumin seeds 2 tsp fennel seeds Salt to taste To serve: fresh coriander  Method  Wash and drain the lentils a few times (until the water isn&amp;rsquo;t cloudy from the starch).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Egg Bhuna</title>
      <link>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/egg-bhuna/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 21:42:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/egg-bhuna/</guid>
      <description>Recipe taken from: Fatima Cooks - Anda Bhuna
Ingredients Serves 2
 1 medium onion, sliced 4 cloves garlic, minced small piece ginger, minced 2 medium tomatoes, sliced 4 hard boiled eggs salt, to taste 0.75 tsp red chilli powder 0.75 tsp cumin powder 0.75 tsp coriander powder 0.5 tsp turmeric powder  Method  In a pan, heat your oil and add the onions, garlic and ginger. Saute till golden, but ensure that the onions do not burn Add the tomatoes, all the spices and a splash of water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Murgh Makhani Butter Tofu 2</title>
      <link>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/murgh-makhani-butter-tofu-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 19:28:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/murgh-makhani-butter-tofu-2/</guid>
      <description>Recipe taken from : &amp;lt;a href=https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=a03U45jFxOI target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Youtube - Get Curried - Butter Chicken
Ingredients For the chicken
 300 gms Chicken breast boneless 1 tbsp Ginger garlic paste 1 tbsp Red chilli powder Salt to taste Oil to pan fry  For the gravy
 500 gms roughly slit tomatoes 100 gms roughly cut onions 1 tbsp garlic paste 50 gms cashew 1 tsp kasoori methi 1/2 tsp garam masala 4 tbsp sugar 2 tbsp kashmiri chilli powder 5 tbsp butter 3 tbsp cream 2 tbsp malt vinegar / 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Murgh Makhani Butter Tofu</title>
      <link>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/murgh-makhani-butter-tofu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 19:04:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/murgh-makhani-butter-tofu/</guid>
      <description>Recipe taken from: Youtube - Videojug - Murgh Makhni
Its for chicken so lets adapt for tofu&amp;hellip;
Ingredients For the chicken/tofu  500g chicken/tofu 50g garlic and ginger paste 0.5 tsp salt 65ml natural yogurt 0.5 tsp kashmiri chilli powder 0.5 tbsp vegetable oil 0.5 tsp garam masala powder  Sauce  40ml vegetable oil 5 cardamon pods 5 cloves 4 bay leaves 6 green chillies 15g root ginger finely chopped 750g of fresh tomatoes 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rogan Josh</title>
      <link>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/rogan-josh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2019 16:15:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/rogan-josh/</guid>
      <description>Recipe taken from : You - Rogon bosh
Ingredients  4 garlic cloves 4cm piece fresh ginger 3 fresh red chillies 1 tbsp tomato purée 60ml water 1 large aubergine 3 tbsp vegetable oil 4 green cardamom pods 1 onion 6 black peppercorns 1 bay leaf 1½cm cinnamon stick 1 tsp sugar 1 tsp ground cumin 2 tsp ground coriander 100g coconut yoghurt large pinch of garam masala handful coriander, to serve handful desiccated coconut flakes, to serve salt  Method  Peel the garlic and ginger and put them into the liquidiser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creamy Coconut Lentil Curry</title>
      <link>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/creamy-coconut-lentil-curry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2019 15:08:04 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/creamy-coconut-lentil-curry/</guid>
      <description>Recipe taken from : The Endless Meal - Creamy Coconut Lentil Curry
Ingredients  2 tablespoons coconut oil 1 tablespoon each: cumin seeds and coriander seeds 1 head of garlic, chopped (10–12 cloves) 1 28-ounce can of crushed tomatoes 2 tablespoons ginger, chopped 1 tablespoon turmeric 2 teaspoons sea salt 1 cup dried brown lentils 1–2 teaspoons cayenne powder, optional 1 15-ounce can coconut milk A few handfuls of cherry tomatoes 1 cup chopped cilantro  Method  Heat the coconut oil in a large pot or skillet over medium-high heat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian Butter Tofu</title>
      <link>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/butter-tofu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2019 13:31:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/butter-tofu/</guid>
      <description>Recipe taken from : Feasting at Home - Indian Butter Chicken or Cauliflower
Ingredients  1 mug of rice / 2 mugs of water - serves 3 400g of natural tofu 1 tablespoon of garam masala 2 tablespoons ghee (or coconut or olive oil) 1 onion, finely diced 1 cinnamon stick serano chilies ( or sub 1 jalapeno) split in half lengthwise, ( leave tops in tact) 4 fat garlic cloves- finely minced 1 tablespoon ginger finely minced ( or use paste) ½ teaspoon fennel seeds ( optional) ½ teaspoon cumin seeds ( optional) ½ teaspoon mustard seeds ( optional) 1 can diced tomatoes or tomato puree ( or sub 2 medium tomatoes, diced with their juices) 200ml water or stock 1 tablespoon garam masala spice ( see notes) 2 teaspoons dried fenugreek leaves (optional, but elevates the dish substantially) 1 teaspoon chili powder 1 teaspoon paprika ( do NOT use smoked paprika, if you don’t have regular, just leave it out!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
