<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Indian on Well lets take a look at it, Mr Gumby!</title>
    <link>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/tags/indian/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Indian on Well lets take a look at it, Mr Gumby!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 00:05:54 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/tags/indian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fish Curry but with Aubergine!</title>
      <link>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/fish-curry-aubergine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 00:05:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/fish-curry-aubergine/</guid>
      <description>Recipe taken from: Telegraph - Rick Stein - Fish Curry
Ingredients  2 tbsp vegetable oil 1 tbsp yellow mustard seeds 1 large onion, finely chopped 3 garlic cloves, crushed 30 fresh curry leaves (from ethnic shops) 2 tsp Kashmiri chilli powder 1/2tsp hot chilli powder (see above) 2 tsp ground coriander 2 tsp turmeric 14oz/400g can chopped tomatoes 3 1/2floz/100ml tamarind water (see below) 2 green chillies, each sliced lengthways into 6 pieces, with seeds (leave these out if you are chilli-sensitive) 1 teaspoon salt lb 9oz/700g snapper fillets, or other white fish, cut into 5cm chunks or 2 aubergines to make it veggie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Egg Bhuna</title>
      <link>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/egg-bhuna/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 21:42:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/egg-bhuna/</guid>
      <description>Recipe taken from: Fatima Cooks - Anda Bhuna
Ingredients Serves 2
 1 medium onion, sliced 4 cloves garlic, minced small piece ginger, minced 2 medium tomatoes, sliced 4 hard boiled eggs salt, to taste 0.75 tsp red chilli powder 0.75 tsp cumin powder 0.75 tsp coriander powder 0.5 tsp turmeric powder  Method  In a pan, heat your oil and add the onions, garlic and ginger. Saute till golden, but ensure that the onions do not burn Add the tomatoes, all the spices and a splash of water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Murgh Makhani Butter Tofu 2</title>
      <link>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/murgh-makhani-butter-tofu-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 19:28:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/murgh-makhani-butter-tofu-2/</guid>
      <description>Recipe taken from : &amp;lt;a href=https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=a03U45jFxOI target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Youtube - Get Curried - Butter Chicken
Ingredients For the chicken
 300 gms Chicken breast boneless 1 tbsp Ginger garlic paste 1 tbsp Red chilli powder Salt to taste Oil to pan fry  For the gravy
 500 gms roughly slit tomatoes 100 gms roughly cut onions 1 tbsp garlic paste 50 gms cashew 1 tsp kasoori methi 1/2 tsp garam masala 4 tbsp sugar 2 tbsp kashmiri chilli powder 5 tbsp butter 3 tbsp cream 2 tbsp malt vinegar / 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Murgh Makhani Butter Tofu</title>
      <link>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/murgh-makhani-butter-tofu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 19:04:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/murgh-makhani-butter-tofu/</guid>
      <description>Recipe taken from: Youtube - Videojug - Murgh Makhni
Its for chicken so lets adapt for tofu&amp;hellip;
Ingredients For the chicken/tofu  500g chicken/tofu 50g garlic and ginger paste 0.5 tsp salt 65ml natural yogurt 0.5 tsp kashmiri chilli powder 0.5 tbsp vegetable oil 0.5 tsp garam masala powder  Sauce  40ml vegetable oil 5 cardamon pods 5 cloves 4 bay leaves 6 green chillies 15g root ginger finely chopped 750g of fresh tomatoes 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rogan Josh</title>
      <link>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/rogan-josh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2019 16:15:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/rogan-josh/</guid>
      <description>Recipe taken from : You - Rogon bosh
Ingredients  4 garlic cloves 4cm piece fresh ginger 3 fresh red chillies 1 tbsp tomato purée 60ml water 1 large aubergine 3 tbsp vegetable oil 4 green cardamom pods 1 onion 6 black peppercorns 1 bay leaf 1½cm cinnamon stick 1 tsp sugar 1 tsp ground cumin 2 tsp ground coriander 100g coconut yoghurt large pinch of garam masala handful coriander, to serve handful desiccated coconut flakes, to serve salt  Method  Peel the garlic and ginger and put them into the liquidiser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian Butter Tofu</title>
      <link>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/butter-tofu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2019 13:31:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/butter-tofu/</guid>
      <description>Recipe taken from : Feasting at Home - Indian Butter Chicken or Cauliflower
Ingredients  1 mug of rice / 2 mugs of water - serves 3 400g of natural tofu 1 tablespoon of garam masala 2 tablespoons ghee (or coconut or olive oil) 1 onion, finely diced 1 cinnamon stick serano chilies ( or sub 1 jalapeno) split in half lengthwise, ( leave tops in tact) 4 fat garlic cloves- finely minced 1 tablespoon ginger finely minced ( or use paste) ½ teaspoon fennel seeds ( optional) ½ teaspoon cumin seeds ( optional) ½ teaspoon mustard seeds ( optional) 1 can diced tomatoes or tomato puree ( or sub 2 medium tomatoes, diced with their juices) 200ml water or stock 1 tablespoon garam masala spice ( see notes) 2 teaspoons dried fenugreek leaves (optional, but elevates the dish substantially) 1 teaspoon chili powder 1 teaspoon paprika ( do NOT use smoked paprika, if you don’t have regular, just leave it out!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
