<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wraps on Well lets take a look at it, Mr Gumby!</title>
    <link>http://localhost:63700/tags/wraps/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wraps on Well lets take a look at it, Mr Gumby!</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2019 23:00:57 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:63700/tags/wraps/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Falafel</title>
      <link>http://localhost:63700/fallfel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2019 23:00:57 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:63700/fallfel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recipe taken from:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Recipe taken from:&#xA;&lt;a href=https://www.gimmesomeoven.com/falafel-recipe/ target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Gimme Some Oven - Falafel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 (15-ounce) can chickpeas, rinsed and drained&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 cup fresh parsley leaves, tightly-packed&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 cup fresh cilantro leaves, tightly-packed&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1/2 cup diced red or yellow onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1/3 cup flour (such as all-purpose, white whole wheat, chickpea, or a 1:1 gluten-free flour)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 tablespoon fresh lemon juice&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 1/2 teaspoons baking powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 1/2 teaspoons ground cumin&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon fine sea salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1/2 teaspoon black pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;6 small garlic cloves, peeled and roughly chopped&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;4–6 tablespoons high-heat oil (such as avocado oil, grapeseed oil or vegetable oil)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;for serving: pita bread, chopped lettuce, sliced red onions, sliced tomatoes, tzatziki sauce, tahini sauce and/or hummus&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;method&#34;&gt;Method&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Roughly purée your ingredients. You can either do this in a food processor (my recommendation), a stand mixer, or a blender.  Pulse until the mixture reaches a fine-grain texture (kind of like coarse sand, ideally not overly mushy).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chill. Transfer the mixture to a bowl, cover and refrigerate for a few hours until chilled.  (Or you can speed this process up by spreading the mixture out in a shallow layer and popping it in the freezer for 30-45 minutes until chilled.)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Form into patties.  Use a medium (2-tablespoon) cookie scoop or a spoon to scoop out 2 tablespoons of the mixture, and then use your hands to shape it into a ball.  Lay the ball on a parchment-covered sheet, then gently flatten it slightly with your hand so that it is about 1/2-inch thick.  Repeat with the remaining dough mixture.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pan-fry the falafel.  Heat the oil over medium-heat.  Then carefully add about 4-5 falafel to the oil and cook for about 2-3 minutes per side until browned and crispy.  Transfer the falafels to a plate lined with paper-towels to soak up any extra oil.  Repeat with the remaining falafels.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Serve! Then serve them up while they’re nice and warm and crispy, and enjoy!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;picture&#34;&gt;Picture&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:63700/food/images/IMG_1949-2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;drawing&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;/&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
