<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Asian on Well lets take a look at it, Mr Gumby!</title>
    <link>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/food/asian/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Asian on Well lets take a look at it, Mr Gumby!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 00:41:47 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/food/asian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tofu With Garlic Sauce</title>
      <link>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/tofu-with-garlic-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 20:49:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/tofu-with-garlic-sauce/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients For the tofu
 600 g medium-firm tofu 2 tablespoon corn flour 2 tablespoon cooking oil  For the sauce
 1 tablespoon cooking oil 1 teaspoon minced ginger 1 tablespoon minced garlic 2 fresh chilli, finely chopped ½ tablespoon Sichuan chilli bean paste 1 ½ tablespoon Shaoxing rice wine 1 ½ tablespoon black rice vinegar 1 tablespoon sugar 3 tablespoon water 1 tablespoon corn flour 1 stalk spring onion, finely chopped Sesame seeds  Method Tofu</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapo Tofu</title>
      <link>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/mapo-tofu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 16:57:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/mapo-tofu/</guid>
      <description>This is a sort of botch together of many recipes.
 Authentic mapo tofu   Vegetarian mapo tofu 
 Mapo eggplant 
  Ingredients  1 aubergine, cut into inch size chunks 400g silken tofu cut into 2cm cubes 250-350g mushrooms blended into coarse particulates 1 tablespoon peanut oil (or vegetable oil) 2 teaspoons Sichuan peppercorns 1 1/2 to 2 tablespoons doubanjiang 4-6 spring onions, sliced with some green part reserved for garnish 2 cloves garlic, minced 1” (2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sichuan Style Aubergine</title>
      <link>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/sichuan-style-aubergine/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 15:32:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/sichuan-style-aubergine/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  3 long Chinese aubergines (about 600g) or small green type - I prefer the small green as they are crunchy! Sea salt 2 Tbsp vegetable oil 1 tsp Sichuan peppercorns, coarsely crushed - substitute with crushed coriander seeds, crushed pepper corns and a small amount of grated lemon 1 green chillis, thinly sliced 2 Tbsp doubanjiang 4 garlic cloves, finely chopped 2.5cm knob of ginger, grated 1 spring onion, thinly sliced Handful of coriander leaves, roughly chopped (optional) Steamed jasmine rice, to serve  Yu xiang sauce</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chinese Egg Plant With Garlic Sauce</title>
      <link>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/chinese-egg-plant-garlic-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 19:45:27 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/chinese-egg-plant-garlic-sauce/</guid>
      <description>Recipe taken from: All Recipes - Chinese Eggplant with Garlic Soy Sauce
Ingredients Serves: 6
 3 tablespoons vegetable oil 4 Chinese eggplants, halved lengthways, then cut into 2cm slices 1 cup (250ml) water 1 tablespoon crushed dried red chilli flakes 3 garlic cloves 1 tablespoon white sugar 1 teaspoon cornflour 2 tablespoons soy sauce 2 tablespoons oyster sauce (or vegetarian alternative!)  Method Preparation:10min Cook:15min Ready in:25min
 Heat the oil in a wok or frypan over high heat.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
