<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Miscellaneous on Well lets take a look at it, Mr Gumby!</title>
    <link>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/food/misc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Miscellaneous on Well lets take a look at it, Mr Gumby!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 00:41:47 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/food/misc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Benj&#39;s Essential Sausage Casserole</title>
      <link>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/sausage-casserole/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 16:39:16 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/sausage-casserole/</guid>
      <description>Benj&amp;rsquo;s essential sausage casserole with a few add-ons and maybe some things i&amp;rsquo;ve forgotten.
Ingredients  6 Herby Bangers - Tesco own brand veggie sausage. They&amp;rsquo;re bangin&#39; bangers 400g tin Butter beans 300ml water 100ml Red wine or more&amp;hellip; OR a red wine stock pot! - my new favourite thing. Veg Stock pot 3 handfuls of Kale 400g tin of chopped tomato Sprig of Thyme 1 Onion - chopped lengthways 200g mushrooms 1 tsp chilli powder 3 cloves of garlic  To Serve</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Panang Curry Paste</title>
      <link>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/panang-curry-paste/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 13:27:45 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/panang-curry-paste/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve made this a fair few times! It&amp;rsquo;s definitely one of my go to pastes! Recipe comes from here
Ingredients Spices
 1 cinnamon stick 2 star anise 10 cardamom shells removed - or substitute with regular cardamom pods 10 whole cloves 2 tbsp coriander seeds 1 tbsp black peppercorns 2 tbsp cumin seeds  Other Ingredients
 3 stems lemongrass finely sliced - or substitute with 3 tbsp jarred/sliced lemongrass 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red Onion Soup</title>
      <link>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/red_onion_soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 13:24:36 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/red_onion_soup/</guid>
      <description>One of my Grandmas recipes for red onion soup I found whilst rummaging around her stack of recipes she has in her kitchen. This is one of the few that didn&amp;rsquo;t involve copious amounts of meat! I found this particular recipe quite the riddle.
Ingredients  2 oz butter 2lb red onion thinly sliced 1 tbsp veg oil 1 tsp salt ½ tsp brown sugar 1½ oz plain flour 3 pints brown stock ½ pint stout or brown ale  Method  Gently cook onions in butter and oil in a large pan for about 15 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Green Tomato Chutney</title>
      <link>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/green_tomato_chutney/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 13:00:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/green_tomato_chutney/</guid>
      <description>This is a recipe from my grandmas sister Ruby.
Ingredients  1kg green tomatoes 500g white onion 500g apples 25g salt 8oz raisons 4oz sultanas 1 litre malt vinegar 350g demera sugar  Method  Slice or mince tomatoes, apples, onions Add raisins, salt, vinegar Simmer for 90 minutes Add sugar Cook until thick  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tomato Soup</title>
      <link>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/tomato-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 21:04:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/tomato-soup/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Roasted tomatoes:
 1kg tomatoes, cut in half if using plum or into 5mm strips if not 6 cloves garlic, peeled 3 tablespoons olive oil Freshly ground salt and pepper  Caramelized onions:
 ½ tablespoon olive oil 2 yellow onions, thinly sliced  Additions to the soup:
 10g basil leaves ½ teaspoon dried oregano 200-500ml cups water or vegetarian broth, depending on how thick you want the soup Freshly ground salt and pepper, to taste  Method  Preheat oven to 200C Roast tomato&amp;rsquo;s with garlic and olive oil for 40 mins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beetroot Dip</title>
      <link>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/beetroot-dip/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 20:24:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/beetroot-dip/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 large beetroot - cooked 1/2 tsp cumin 1/2 tsp ground coriander 3 cloves of garlic Pinch of salt 300ml greek yogurt 1/2 lemon juiced  Method  Put it in a blender and blend it!  Comments All the above ingredients are a rough estimation. Add bits at a time and enjoy the ride.
Pictures </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kale Salad</title>
      <link>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/kale-salad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 08:01:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/kale-salad/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 sweet potatoes cut into 2cm cubes 400g (1 can) chick peas 1 tsp ground cumin 1 tsp ground paprika 200g of kale chilli flakes olive oil 20g chopped parsley  Dressing
 150g cashews 2 garlic cloves (roasted) 6 tbsp of almond milk 2 tsp dijon mustard 1 lemon - juiced pinch of salt  Optional
 Flaked almonds - toasted  Method  Preheat oven to 190 Celsius Mix together sweet potato, chick peas, cumin, and paprika in a bowl with a pinch of salt and olive oil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gorgonzola Pasta</title>
      <link>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/gorgonzola-pasta/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 21:38:43 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/gorgonzola-pasta/</guid>
      <description>Sam would describe this recipe as &amp;lsquo;real indulgent&amp;rsquo;. Thanks Sam :)
Ingredients  4 shallots - finely chopped 400g tin of chopped tomatoes 1/2 tsp chilli flakes 200ml single cream 250g of Gorgonzola - roughly chopped 2 cloves of garlic - finely chopped 20g basil - finely chopped  Method  Add a good glug of olive oil to a pan on medium heat and add the shallots. After one minute add the chilli flakes and garlic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>African Peanut Stew</title>
      <link>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/african-peanut-stew/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 21:26:43 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/african-peanut-stew/</guid>
      <description>Stew Ingredients  1-2 tbsp peanut oil 500g sweet potato - peeled and diced 1 x 400g tin of black-eyed peas, drained and rinsed / or black beans 1 x green chilli 3 tbsp tomato puree 1 x 400g tin of chopped tomatoes 500ml vegetable stock 125g smooth peanut butter 200g spinach 1 tbsp lemon juice Handful of corriander 2 spring onions  Paste Ingredients  2 onions - roughly chopped 5 garlic cloves - roughly chopped 2 inch piece of ginger - roughly chopped 1 tsp paprika 2 tsp ground coriander 1 tsp ground turmeric 2 tsp cumin 1 tsp ground fenugreek 1 green chilli  Method  Blitz paste ingredients Add oil to pan and saute paste for 10 mins on a low/medium heat Add sweet potato, black eyed pas/beans, 1/2 green chilli, and tomato puree.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lentil Ragu</title>
      <link>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/lentil-ragu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 20:50:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/lentil-ragu/</guid>
      <description>An easy meal with minimal effort that gets better with age!
Ingredients puy lentil and mushroom ragu (serves 8-10)
 2 tablespoons olive oil 2 carrots, finely chopped 2 onions, finely chopped 300g chestnut mushrooms, finely chopped 4 cloves garlic, finely chopped 250g puy lentils 200ml red wine 2 tablespoon tomato puree 2x 400g tin of chopped tomatoes 1 litre vegetable stock 3 bay leaf 1 teaspoon dried oregano salt &amp;amp; pepper 20g chopped basil  Method  Fry onions and carrot in olive oil on a low/medium heat until onions become translucent (5-8 mins) Add the garlic and mushrooms until cooked through (5 mins) Add lentils, red wine, and tomato puree.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spicy Beetroot Sandwich Filler</title>
      <link>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/beetroot-sandwich/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 17:19:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/beetroot-sandwich/</guid>
      <description>This sandwich filler comes from Lous friends mum. Its a belter!
Ingrediants  2 grated boiled beetroot or 200g of shredded beetroot 100g Philadelphia cream cheese 1 Green chili Pepper and salt to taste 50g Grated cheddar  Method  add everything to a blender and coarsely blend  Picture </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banana Bread</title>
      <link>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/banana-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 21:22:27 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/banana-bread/</guid>
      <description>This recipe comes from my friend Tom who adapted the BBC Goodfoods recipe. For my take I don&amp;rsquo;t add chocolate to it because chocolate belongs in chocolate bars. Link to Tom&amp;rsquo;s website Here!
Ingredients  125g margarine (or butter) 125g sugar (half white, half brown) 2 small eggs, beaten 125g flour (farine bise) 1 tsp baking powder 2 ripe bananas Handful walnuts Handful dark chocolate chunks  Method  Heat the oven to 190C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roasted Tomato</title>
      <link>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/roasted-tomato/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 20:49:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/roasted-tomato/</guid>
      <description>A quick recipe from my house mate Lou. A great afternoon snack!
Ingredients  1 Beef tomato or tomato of your choice cut into 2-3cm chunks A few sprigs of thyme 3 Cloves of garlic - whole Olive oil Balsamic vinegar  Method  Preheat oven to 180 C Add tomato, thyme and garlic into oven tray and cover in oil Season with salt and pepper Roast for 20- 30 minutes Drizzle balsamic vinegar and remove thyme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leek and Mushroom Pie</title>
      <link>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/leek-and-mushroom-pie/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 22:59:08 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/leek-and-mushroom-pie/</guid>
      <description>Recipe taken from : Easy Peasy Foodie
Ingredients  25 g butter 2 small leeks sliced 150 g chestnut mushrooms thinly sliced 200 g Quorn chicken pieces (or 400g leftover roast chicken or 2 small chicken breasts) 1 tablespoon plain flour 1 vegetable stock cube (or 1 chicken stock cube) 300 ml boiling water 300 ml crème fraîche 1 tablespoon thyme leaves Salt and pepper 500 g block puff pastry A small amount of milk 4 large Potato&amp;rsquo;s  Method  Pre-heat the oven to 220C / 200C fan / gas mark 7 / 425F.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beetroot Risotto</title>
      <link>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/beetroot-riossotto/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 09:32:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/beetroot-riossotto/</guid>
      <description>Recipe taken from : BBC Good Food
Ingredients  500g fresh beetroot 2 tbsp olive oil knob of butter 1 onion, finely chopped 1 garlic clove, finely chopped 250g risotto rice 150ml white wine 700ml hot vegetable stock handful grated parmesan (or vegetarian alternative) 4 tbsp soured cream handful chopped dill  Method   Heat oven to 180C/fan 160C/gas 4. Peel and trim the beetroots (use kitchen gloves if you don’t want your hands to get stained) and cut into large wedges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Pot Mexican Quinoa</title>
      <link>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/one-pot-mexican-quinoa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 09:15:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/one-pot-mexican-quinoa/</guid>
      <description>Recipe taken from: Damn Delicious
Ingredients  1 tablespoon olive oil 2 cloves garlic, minced 1 jalapeno, minced 1 cup quinoa 1 cup vegetable broth 1 (15-ounce) can black beans, drained and rinsed 1 (14.5 oz) can fire-roasted diced tomatoes 1 cup corn kernels, frozen, canned or roasted 1 teaspoon chili powder 1/2 teaspoon cumin Kosher salt and freshly ground black pepper, to taste 1 avocado, halved, seeded, peeled and diced Juice of 1 lime 2 tablespoons chopped fresh cilantro leaves  Method  Heat olive oil in a large skillet over medium high heat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flapjack</title>
      <link>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/flapjack/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2019 14:09:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mybrainhertz.co.uk/flapjack/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  250g porridge oats 125g butter 125g brown sugar 3 tbsp golden syrup 50g walnuts 25g almonds  Method  Preheat oven to 180°C On a low heat add buter, sugar, and golden syrup to a pan. Heat until sugar has lost granularity Add porridge oats, walnuts, almonds, whatever else you want to add. Line a 20x20cm baking tray and pour oat mixture in. Place in oven for 20 mins or until golden brown.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
