<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>An Attempt to Organise my Mind</title>
    <link>https://furrah.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on An Attempt to Organise my Mind</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 21:42:02 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://furrah.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Egg Bhuna</title>
      <link>https://furrah.github.io/egg-bhuna/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 21:42:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://furrah.github.io/egg-bhuna/</guid>
      <description>Recipe taken from: http://fatimacooks.net/recipe/anda-bhuna/
Ingredients Serves 2
 1 medium onion, sliced 4 cloves garlic, minced small piece ginger, minced 2 medium tomatoes, sliced 4 hard boiled eggs salt, to taste 0.75 tsp red chilli powder 0.75 tsp cumin powder 0.75 tsp coriander powder 0.5 tsp turmeric powder  Method  In a pan, heat your oil and add the onions, garlic and ginger. Saute till golden, but ensure that the onions do not burn Add the tomatoes, all the spices and a splash of water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tabbouleh</title>
      <link>https://furrah.github.io/tabbouleh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2019 21:57:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://furrah.github.io/tabbouleh/</guid>
      <description>Recipe taken from https://www.bbcgoodfood.com/recipe/halloumi-broccoli-tabbouleh-honey-harissa-dressing
Ingredients  140g couscous 300g broccoli florets 6 spring onions , finely sliced 150g cherry tomato, quartered large bunch parsley, finely chopped small bunch mint, finely chopped juice 2 lemons, zest of ½ lemon 2½ tbsp extra virgin olive oil 1½ tbsp harissa or sriracha 1 tbsp clear honey 2 x 250g packs halloumi cheese, cut into 1cm-thick slices 25g toasted flaked almond or fresh.  Method  Put the couscous into a bowl and cover with boiling water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Morocco - The Atlas Mountains</title>
      <link>https://furrah.github.io/morroco/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2019 15:21:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://furrah.github.io/morroco/</guid>
      <description>In August 2018 my friends and I visited the Atlas mountains of Morocco and walked up Mount Toubkal. Despite my camera having a horrendous light leak I managed to get a few photos of that walk.
We had envisioned a hike though the Atlas mountains off the typical tourist route, following the Berber trails. It became apparent after the first day of ascent that we weren&amp;rsquo;t equipped for this route. I remember feeling the exposure of the desert mountains, not being able to hide from the sun and slipping down constantly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flapjack</title>
      <link>https://furrah.github.io/flapjack/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2019 14:09:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://furrah.github.io/flapjack/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  250g porridge oats 125g butter 125g brown sugar 3 tbsp golden syrup 50g walnuts 25g almonds  Method  Preheat oven to 180°C On a low heat add buter, sugar, and golden syrup to a pan. Heat until sugar has lost granularity Add porridge oats, walnuts, almonds, whatever else you want to add. Line a 20x20cm baking tray and pour oat mixture in. Place in oven for 20 mins or until golden brown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Precision Op Amp Gain Adjustment with DACs</title>
      <link>https://furrah.github.io/op-amp-gain-adjustment-dac/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 22:24:10 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://furrah.github.io/op-amp-gain-adjustment-dac/</guid>
      <description>Basic non-inverting operational amplifier design involves a feedback resistor and a gain resistor. These are shown in the figure below as R2 as the feedback resistor and R1 as the gain resistor. The formula for calculating the gain is;
\begin{align} Gain = \frac{R_2}{R_1} + 1 \end{align}
It would be nice to adjust the gain of this amplifier. This can be done achieved easily with a potentiometer in place of R1 or R2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chinese Egg Plant With Garlic Sauce</title>
      <link>https://furrah.github.io/chinese-egg-plant-garlic-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 19:45:27 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://furrah.github.io/chinese-egg-plant-garlic-sauce/</guid>
      <description>Recipe taken from: http://allrecipes.com.au/recipe/10769/chinese-eggplant-with-garlic-soy-sauce.aspx
Ingredients Serves: 6
 3 tablespoons vegetable oil 4 Chinese eggplants, halved lengthways, then cut into 2cm slices 1 cup (250ml) water 1 tablespoon crushed dried red chilli flakes 3 garlic cloves 1 tablespoon white sugar 1 teaspoon cornflour 2 tablespoons soy sauce 2 tablespoons oyster sauce  Method Preparation:10min Cook:15min Ready in:25min
 Heat the oil in a wok or frypan over high heat. Add the eggplant and stir the eggplant until soft, about 4 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Murgh Makhani Butter Tofu 2</title>
      <link>https://furrah.github.io/murgh-makhani-butter-tofu-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 19:28:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://furrah.github.io/murgh-makhani-butter-tofu-2/</guid>
      <description>Recipe taken from : https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=a03U45jFxOI
Ingredients For the chicken
 300 gms Chicken breast boneless 1 tbsp Ginger garlic paste 1 tbsp Red chilli powder Salt to taste Oil to pan fry  For the gravy
 500 gms roughly slit tomatoes 100 gms roughly cut onions 1 tbsp garlic paste 50 gms cashew 1 tsp kasoori methi 1&amp;frasl;2 tsp garam masala 4 tbsp sugar 2 tbsp kashmiri chilli powder 5 tbsp butter 3 tbsp cream 2 tbsp malt vinegar / 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Murgh Makhani Butter Tofu</title>
      <link>https://furrah.github.io/murgh-makhani-butter-tofu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 19:04:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://furrah.github.io/murgh-makhani-butter-tofu/</guid>
      <description>Recipe taken from https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ba0Lsa5vdM4
Its for chicken so lets adapt for tofu&amp;hellip;
Ingredients For the chicken/tofu  500g chicken/tofu 50g garlic and ginger paste 0.5 tsp salt 65ml natural yogurt 0.5 tsp kashmiri chilli powder 0.5 tbsp vegetable oil 0.5 tsp garam masala powder  Sauce  40ml vegetable oil 5 cardamon pods 5 cloves 4 bay leaves 6 green chillies 15g root ginger finely chopped 750g of fresh tomatoes 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Falafel</title>
      <link>https://furrah.github.io/fallfel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2019 23:00:57 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://furrah.github.io/fallfel/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 (15-ounce) can chickpeas, rinsed and drained 1 cup fresh parsley leaves, tightly-packed 1 cup fresh cilantro leaves, tightly-packed 1&amp;frasl;2 cup diced red or yellow onion 1&amp;frasl;3 cup flour (such as all-purpose, white whole wheat, chickpea, or a 1:1 gluten-free flour) 1 tablespoon fresh lemon juice 1 1&amp;frasl;2 teaspoons baking powder 1 1&amp;frasl;2 teaspoons ground cumin 1 teaspoon fine sea salt 1&amp;frasl;2 teaspoon black pepper 6 small garlic cloves, peeled and roughly chopped 4–6 tablespoons high-heat oil (such as avocado oil, grapeseed oil or vegetable oil) for serving: pita bread, chopped lettuce, sliced red onions, sliced tomatoes, tzatziki sauce, tahini sauce and/or hummus  Method  Roughly purée your ingredients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lancaster</title>
      <link>https://furrah.github.io/lancaster-bowland-forest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2019 22:04:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://furrah.github.io/lancaster-bowland-forest/</guid>
      <description>This photo was taken on a walk around Bowland forest whilst I was studying at the University of Lancaster. It must be dated around 2016 and was shot on a Rolleiflex camera with Rollei IR400 Film. 
Ribblehead viaduct! This was taken on a separate trip. My friend Cristina convinced me and my friend Zane that this was infact the viaduct from Harry Potter that the Hogwarts Express crossed! It is not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FPGA I2C Wishbone Interface and Testing </title>
      <link>https://furrah.github.io/i2c-wishbone-interface-fpga/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2019 20:04:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://furrah.github.io/i2c-wishbone-interface-fpga/</guid>
      <description>Requirements  Lua 5.14+ (recommended 5.15) (https://github.com/rjpcomputing/luaforwindows/releases/tag/v5.1.5-52) wbgen2 https://www.ohwr.org/project/wishbone-gen MCP2221A USB2.0 to I2C/UART Protocol Converter with GPIO  Any USB to I2C device will work.   Creating an I2C wishbone interface for FPGA The wishbone interface acts as a bridge between the FPGA and external signals containing a master and a slave. In this example the FPGA will be acting as an I2C slave with two registers;
 1 read/write 1 read only.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparison of Integrated Noise Spectrum of JFET and BJT input Operational Amplifiers</title>
      <link>https://furrah.github.io/integrated-noise-spectrum/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2019 19:04:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://furrah.github.io/integrated-noise-spectrum/</guid>
      <description>Reference material: https://training.ti.com/sites/default/files/docs/Op%20Amp%20Tech%20Overview_0.pdf
When developing precision DC systems BJT transistors are the way to go. Be careful when selecting an op amp based on its datasheet noise characteristics. At DC we are interested in the 1/f noise, which as the name suggests increases as we approach DC. an example is shown below comparing the JFET input OPA827 and the BJT input OPA227.
Figure1 - CMOS, BJT, and JFET flicker noise</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rogan Josh</title>
      <link>https://furrah.github.io/rogan-josh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2019 16:15:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://furrah.github.io/rogan-josh/</guid>
      <description>Recipe taken from : https://www.you.co.uk/rogan-bosh-recipe/
Ingredients  4 garlic cloves 4cm piece fresh ginger 3 fresh red chillies 1 tbsp tomato purée 60ml water 1 large aubergine 3 tbsp vegetable oil 4 green cardamom pods 1 onion 6 black peppercorns 1 bay leaf 1½cm cinnamon stick 1 tsp sugar 1 tsp ground cumin 2 tsp ground coriander 100g coconut yoghurt large pinch of garam masala handful coriander, to serve handful desiccated coconut flakes, to serve salt  Method  Peel the garlic and ginger and put them into the liquidiser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creamy Coconut Lentil Curry</title>
      <link>https://furrah.github.io/creamy-coconut-lentil-curry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2019 15:08:04 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://furrah.github.io/creamy-coconut-lentil-curry/</guid>
      <description>Recipe taken from : https://www.theendlessmeal.com/creamy-coconut-lentil-curry/
Ingredients  2 tablespoons coconut oil 1 tablespoon each: cumin seeds and coriander seeds 1 head of garlic, chopped (10–12 cloves) 1 28-ounce can of crushed tomatoes 2 tablespoons ginger, chopped 1 tablespoon turmeric 2 teaspoons sea salt 1 cup dried brown lentils 1–2 teaspoons cayenne powder, optional 1 15-ounce can coconut milk A few handfuls of cherry tomatoes 1 cup chopped cilantro  Method  Heat the coconut oil in a large pot or skillet over medium-high heat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian Butter Tofu</title>
      <link>https://furrah.github.io/butter-tofu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2019 13:31:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://furrah.github.io/butter-tofu/</guid>
      <description>Recipe taken from : https://www.feastingathome.com/indian-butter-chicken-or-cauliflower/
Ingredients  1 mug of rice / 2 mugs of water - serves 3 400g of natural tofu 1 tablespoon of garam masala 2 tablespoons ghee (or coconut or olive oil) 1 onion, finely diced 1 cinnamon stick serano chilies ( or sub 1 jalapeno) split in half lengthwise, ( leave tops in tact) 4 fat garlic cloves- finely minced 1 tablespoon ginger finely minced ( or use paste) ½ teaspoon fennel seeds ( optional) ½ teaspoon cumin seeds ( optional) ½ teaspoon mustard seeds ( optional) 1 can diced tomatoes or tomato puree ( or sub 2 medium tomatoes, diced with their juices) 200ml water or stock 1 tablespoon garam masala spice ( see notes) 2 teaspoons dried fenugreek leaves (optional, but elevates the dish substantially) 1 teaspoon chili powder 1 teaspoon paprika ( do NOT use smoked paprika, if you don’t have regular, just leave it out!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>