<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Photography on An Attempt to Organise my Mind</title>
    <link>https://furrah.github.io/photography/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Photography on An Attempt to Organise my Mind</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2019 15:21:48 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://furrah.github.io/photography/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Morocco - The Atlas Mountains</title>
      <link>https://furrah.github.io/morroco/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2019 15:21:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://furrah.github.io/morroco/</guid>
      <description>In August 2018 my friends and I visited the Atlas mountains of Morocco and walked up Mount Toubkal. Despite my camera having a horrendous light leak I managed to get a few photos of that walk.
We had envisioned a hike though the Atlas mountains off the typical tourist route, following the Berber trails. It became apparent after the first day of ascent that we weren&amp;rsquo;t equipped for this route. I remember feeling the exposure of the desert mountains, not being able to hide from the sun and slipping down constantly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lancaster</title>
      <link>https://furrah.github.io/lancaster-bowland-forest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2019 22:04:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://furrah.github.io/lancaster-bowland-forest/</guid>
      <description>This photo was taken on a walk around Bowland forest whilst I was studying at the University of Lancaster. It must be dated around 2016 and was shot on a Rolleiflex camera with Rollei IR400 Film. 
Ribblehead viaduct! This was taken on a separate trip. My friend Cristina convinced me and my friend Zane that this was infact the viaduct from Harry Potter that the Hogwarts Express crossed! It is not.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>