<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Middle Eastern on Well lets take a look at it, Mr Gumby!</title>
    <link>http://localhost:63700/food/middle-eastern/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Middle Eastern on Well lets take a look at it, Mr Gumby!</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 08:30:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:63700/food/middle-eastern/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Babaganoush</title>
      <link>http://localhost:63700/babaganoush/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 08:30:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:63700/babaganoush/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1kg Aubergine criss crossed&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2-3 cloves of garlic finely chopped&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2 tablespoons of lemon juice&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;3 tablespoons of tahini&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2 tablespoons extra-virgin olive oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;10-20g chopped fresh flat-leaf parsley&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;¾ teaspoon salt, to taste&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;¼ teaspoon ground cumin&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pinch of smoked paprika&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pomegranate molasses&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;method&#34;&gt;Method&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pre heat oven to 190C&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Criss-cross the aubergines, cover in olive oil, and put in the oven for 40 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Once cooked, drain of water using a colander and smush about with a fork until its pasty.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mix in garlic, lemon juice, tahini, olive oil, parsley, salt, and cumin.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garnish with paprika and pomegranate molasses (as much as you want).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:63700/food/images/IMG_9950.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;drawing&#34; width=&#34;600&#34;/&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Baked Sweet Potatoes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:63700/baked-sweet-potatoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 23:14:24 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:63700/baked-sweet-potatoes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;4 medium (~1/3 lb each) sweet potatoes&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 15-ounce can chickpeas (rinsed and drained)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1/2 Tbsp olive oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1/2 tsp each cumin, coriander, cinnamon, smoked (or regular) paprika&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 pinch sea salt or lemon juice (optional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;garlic-herb-sauce&#34;&gt;Garlic Herb Sauce&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1/4 cup hummus (or tahini)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1/2 medium lemon, juiced (1/2 lemon yields ~1 Tbsp juice)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;3 cloves garlic, minced (3 cloves yield ~1 1/2 Tbsp or 9 g)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Water or unsweetened almond milk (to thin)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sea salt to taste (optional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;toppings&#34;&gt;Toppings&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1/4 cup cherry tomatoes (diced)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1/4 cup chopped parsley (minced)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2 Tbsp lemon juice&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chili garlic sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;instructions&#34;&gt;Instructions&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Preheat oven to 400 degrees F (204 C) and line a large baking sheet with foil.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Rinse and scrub potatoes and cut in half length wise. This will speed cooking time. Otherwise leave whole and bake longer (approximately double the time (45 min – 1 hour).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Toss rinsed and drained chickpeas with olive oil and spices and place on a foil-lined baking sheet.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Rub the sweet potatoes with a bit of olive oil and place face down on the same baking sheet (or another baking sheet depending on size).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;While the sweet potatoes and chickpeas are roasting, prepare your sauce by adding all ingredients to a mixing bowl and whisking to combine, only adding enough water or almond milk to thin so it’s pourable. Taste and adjust seasonings as needed. Add more garlic for more zing, salt for savoriness, lemon juice for freshness, and dill for a more intense herb flavor. I found mine didn’t need anything else.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;NOTE: If you don’t have hummus, tahini (which you can DIY!) will make a great base substitution for the sauce – just adjust the seasonings to accommodate the lack of flavor tahini provides.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Also prepare the parsley-tomato topping by tossing tomato and parsley with lemon juice and setting aside to marinate.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Once sweet potatoes are fork tender and the chickpeas are golden brown – roughly 25 minutes – remove from oven.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;For serving, flip potatoes flesh-side up and smash down the insides a little bit. Then top with chickpeas, garlic herb sauce, parsley-tomato salad, and chili garlic sauce (optional). Serve immediately.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Additional side ideas might include Hummus, Pita Chips, Baba Ganoush, or Persian Eggplant Dip. Enjoy!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:63700/food/images/IMG_9138.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;drawing&#34; width=&#34;600&#34;/&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabbouleh</title>
      <link>http://localhost:63700/tabbouleh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2019 21:57:18 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:63700/tabbouleh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recipe taken from&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bbcgoodfood.com/recipe/halloumi-broccoli-tabbouleh-honey-harissa-dressing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;BBC Good Food - Tabbouleh with Halloumi and Broccoli.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;140g couscous&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;300g broccoli florets&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;6 spring onions , finely sliced&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;150g cherry tomato, quartered&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;large bunch parsley, finely chopped&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;small bunch mint, finely chopped&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;juice 2 lemons, zest of ½ lemon&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2½ tbsp extra virgin olive oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1½ tbsp harissa or sriracha&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 tbsp clear honey&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2 x 250g packs halloumi cheese, cut into 1cm-thick slices&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;25g fresh almonds.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;method&#34;&gt;Method&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Put the couscous into a bowl and cover with boiling water. Cover with cling film and set aside for 5 mins.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Blanch the broccoli for 2 mins, then drain well. Cut it into small pieces or blitz it in a food processor.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fork the broccoli, spring onions, tomatoes, herbs, lemon zest, the juice of 1½ lemons and 2 tbsp oil through the couscous. Season and mix well.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To make the dressing, combine the harissa, honey, remaining lemon juice and oil, and some seasoning.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Heat a non-stick frying pan and cook the halloumi for 1-2 mins on each side until golden. Divide the couscous between the plates, top with the halloumi slices and dressing, then scatter over the almonds (sometimes i like to toast the almonds for a couple of minutes in pan).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I always make this racipe with srirasha sauce. For the sauce I use a ratio of 2:2:1 of lemon,sriracha,honey. Taste and change for desired flavour. I also find fresh almonds are better than toasted.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Falafel</title>
      <link>http://localhost:63700/fallfel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2019 23:00:57 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:63700/fallfel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recipe taken from:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Recipe taken from:&#xA;&lt;a href=https://www.gimmesomeoven.com/falafel-recipe/ target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Gimme Some Oven - Falafel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 (15-ounce) can chickpeas, rinsed and drained&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 cup fresh parsley leaves, tightly-packed&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 cup fresh cilantro leaves, tightly-packed&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1/2 cup diced red or yellow onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1/3 cup flour (such as all-purpose, white whole wheat, chickpea, or a 1:1 gluten-free flour)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 tablespoon fresh lemon juice&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 1/2 teaspoons baking powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 1/2 teaspoons ground cumin&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon fine sea salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1/2 teaspoon black pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;6 small garlic cloves, peeled and roughly chopped&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;4–6 tablespoons high-heat oil (such as avocado oil, grapeseed oil or vegetable oil)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;for serving: pita bread, chopped lettuce, sliced red onions, sliced tomatoes, tzatziki sauce, tahini sauce and/or hummus&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;method&#34;&gt;Method&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Roughly purée your ingredients. You can either do this in a food processor (my recommendation), a stand mixer, or a blender.  Pulse until the mixture reaches a fine-grain texture (kind of like coarse sand, ideally not overly mushy).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chill. Transfer the mixture to a bowl, cover and refrigerate for a few hours until chilled.  (Or you can speed this process up by spreading the mixture out in a shallow layer and popping it in the freezer for 30-45 minutes until chilled.)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Form into patties.  Use a medium (2-tablespoon) cookie scoop or a spoon to scoop out 2 tablespoons of the mixture, and then use your hands to shape it into a ball.  Lay the ball on a parchment-covered sheet, then gently flatten it slightly with your hand so that it is about 1/2-inch thick.  Repeat with the remaining dough mixture.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pan-fry the falafel.  Heat the oil over medium-heat.  Then carefully add about 4-5 falafel to the oil and cook for about 2-3 minutes per side until browned and crispy.  Transfer the falafels to a plate lined with paper-towels to soak up any extra oil.  Repeat with the remaining falafels.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Serve! Then serve them up while they’re nice and warm and crispy, and enjoy!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;picture&#34;&gt;Picture&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:63700/food/images/IMG_1949-2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;drawing&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;/&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
